

#### PROJECT/PROGRAM MANAGER

12301 Silverstream Lane, Manor, Texas 78653

□+1 512 927 6286 | Seanryanholden@gmail.com | 🖬 seanryanholden

## **Summary**

With over ten years in tech and seven years of overlapping project and people management experience in both IT and Sales Operations at Dell Technologies, Sean is a passionate, pervasive link between a business and its consumers. He supported stakeholders ranging from internal end users, developers, product and program managers, to external enterprise and federal customers. As project manager, Sean drove the development and adoption for as well as tracked the successes of high-impact programs inspired by knowledge gained from analytics, market data, testing, as well as meeting with teams of all sizes to create and lead custom tailored solutions. He held audiences ranging from direct reports to vice presidents and has been praised by multiple senior leaders for his high emotional IQ and signature ability to bring a structured approach to modern, complex issues with a focus on the well-being and development of his peers and delivering timely, high quality, and consistent results.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_

Dell Technologies

Advisor, Project/Program Management

Round Rock, Texas Jun 2021 - Feb 2023

• Identified issues through data analytics and end user reporting, performed pre-deployment testing, created group discussions based on these findings with product managers, end users, and developers to **collaborate** and implement a path to completion with a focus on prioritization.

- Drove communication via virtual Teams and Zoom meetings, real-time chat, and organization wide newsletters to ensure each involved party were consistently and accurately updated along with any associated issue in Jira and ServiceNow. Firm believer in the ideal that **you can communicate effectively with anyone regardless of business or technical acumen if you take the time to hear them first**.
- Determined the impact of new issues and ushered their progress end-to-end, potential loss ranging from \$3K to \$30M which determined scope and required bespoke, real-time engagement and creative solutioning for software nested within Oracle, Salesforce, and ServiceNow products.
- Ran scenarios in test environments for feature releases, deployments, and any change published by developers in a Task or Story with **a focus on the user experience**. Worked with stakeholders, signed off on each solution, and cascaded results and change requests to the business.
- Designed and maintained custom metric reporting. Though most internal departments had established, analytical automation and dashboards, this was entirely manual in Commercial Flex Billing and driven by Sean from discovery and analysis to presentations reviewed by vice presidents. Discoveries made from his reporting **led to change** in how Sales was compensated and shaped financial growth in 2023.

Dell Technologies Round Rock, Texas

TECHNICAL SUPPORT MANAGER

Mar 2016 - Jun 2021

- Worked alongside a Project Management Office to develop and lead programs ranging from the creation and adoption of new tools and training to launching a federal IT business new to Dell Technologies. This led to more projects as acting project manager prior to his title change.
- While assisting with projects, Sean also maintained the metric performance of 30+ direct reports through analytics, external and internal feedback, and the review of cases created in Salesforce, his final team outperforming every other group **globally** for two consecutive years.
- Collaborated with Human Resources regularly to **uplift and develop** the performance of IT and technical support representatives and supporting leaders through years of repeated, exemplary performance focused on employee professional growth and work-life balance betterment.
- Interviewed and onboarded **180+** new employees. Created and led a training curriculum designed to turn even the most novice technology users into self-maintained IT personnel at the end of a three-week period through in-class education, discussion, and job shadowing.
- Received **Top Performer** and **Everyday Hero** awards during his period as manager.

Dell Technologies Round Rock, Texas

SENIOR TECHNICIAN · TECHNICAL LEAD · TEAM LEAD

Oct 2012 - Mar 2016

- Supported the direct manager of each frontline team by providing real-time employee support regarding process, policy, and tool usage.
- Created product, tool, and process change training through use knowledge and time assisting frontline employees. These were published and became standard employee training documents, knowledge base articles, and were the foundation for multiple, new program launches.
- Received **Top Performer** and **Significant Contributor** awards during his period as team lead.

#### **Education**

### **Collin County Community College**

GRAPHIC DESIGN, MUSIC BUSINESS

Plano, Texas

Aug 2008 - May 2010

• Focused on front end development and commercial media.

# **Extracurricular Activity**

Dell Technologies | Pride

Round Rock, Texas

Oct 2016 - Feb 2023

CENTRAL TEXAS LIAISON

• Promoted awareness of the employee resource group Pride through campus newsletters, cross-company networking and charity events, as well as ways to support the Austin local LGBTQIA+ community. Spoke at internal and external job fairs as a liaison for Dell Technologies.